# Hsiang-Wei (Eddie) Huang

Email: hsiangwei0903@gmail.com Linkedin: Click here Website: Click here Mobile: (+1) 206-670-7312

#### SUMMARY

I am a current Ph.D. student in the Department of Electrical Computer Engineering at the University of Washington. I am working with Prof. Jenq-Neng Hwang and the Information Processing Lab. My research interests lie around **Single Camera and Multi Camera People and Vehicle Tracking**, **Human Pose Estimation**, **Object Re-Identification** and **Action Recognition**.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Washington Mar 2023 – Present | Seattle

PhD in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Research Interest: Object Tracking, Re-identification, Action Recognition, Video Understanding

University of Washington Sep 2021 – Mar 2023 | Seattle

Master of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering

National Chiao Tung University Sep 2017 – Dec 2020 | Taiwan

Bachelor of Science

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** Python, SQL, C, Matlab

Software Tools: Pytorch, Tensorflow, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Pandas, OpenCV, Linux, Git, AWS, Azure, SQLite3, LaTex

Languages: English, Chinese

#### **HONORS & AWARDS**

### 1st Place, 2024 WACV MaCVi Challenge - UAV-based Multi-Object Tracking and Re-Identification [URL] Sep 2023 - Nov 2023

- Present a meta-data aided re-identification method for long-term multi-object tracking and re-identification.
- Achieved the best performance with an HOTA of 69.5 in the 2024 WACV Maritime Computer Vision Challenge.

# 1st Place, 2024 WACV MaCVi Challenge - USV-based Multi-Object Tracking [URL]

Sep 2023 - Nov 2023

- Present a strong model ensemble method to conduct tracking on USV-based multi-object tracking.
- Achieved the best performance with an HOTA of 21.5 in the 2024 WACV Maritime Computer Vision Challenge.

#### 1st Place, 2023 CVPR AI City Challenge in Multi-Camera People Tracking [URL]

Feb 2023 - Mar 2023

- Present a robust anchor-guided clustering method for multi-camera people tracking and re-identification.
- Achieved the best performance with an IDF1 of 95.36, in the 2023 AI City Challenge Track 1 on the public testing set which consists of data from real and synthetic multi-camera settings.

#### 3rd Place, 2022 ECCV DeeperAction Challenge - SportsMOT Track on Multi-actor Tracking [URL]

Jun 2022 - Sep 2022

- Ranked 3rd place in HOTA among over 130 teams on the final leaderboard.
- Achieved over 73.9% HOTA on sports player tracking in three different sports scenes including basketball, volleyball, and football.
- Paper presented at the ECCV DeeperAction Workshop, 2022.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- Iterative Scale-Up ExpansionIoU and Deep Features Association for Multi-Object Tracking in Sports Hsiang-Wei Huang, Cheng-Yen Yang, Jiacheng Sun, Jenq-Neng Hwang – 2024 WACV Workshop
- Sea You Later: Metadata-Guided Long-Term Re-Identification for UAV-Based Multi-Object Tracking
  Cheng-Yen Yang, Hsiang-Wei Huang, Zhongyu Jiang, Heng-Cheng Kuo, Jie Mei, Jeng-Neng Hwang 2024 WACV Workshop
- A Density-Guided Temporal Attention Transformer for Indiscernible Object Counting in Underwater Videos Cheng-Yen Yang, Hsiang-Wei Huang, Zhongyu Jiang, Hao Wang, Farron Wallace, Jeng-Neng Hwang – IEEE ICASSP 2024
- Boosting Online 3D Multi-Object Tracking through Camera-Radar Cross Check
   Sheng-Yao Kuan, Jen-Hao Cheng, Hsiang-Wei Huang, Jenq-Neng Hwang In submission to 2024 CVPR
- Enhancing Multi-Camera People Tracking with Anchor-Guided Clustering and Spatio-Temporal Consistency ID Re-Assignment Hsiang-Wei Huang, Cheng-Yen Yang, Zhongyu Jiang, Jenq-Neng Hwang – 2023 CVPR Workshop
- Observation Centric and Central Distance Recovery for Athlete Tracking
   Hsiang-Wei Huang, Cheng-Yen Yang, Jenq-Neng Hwang – 2023 WACV Workshop

- Multi-Target Multi-Camera Vehicle Tracking Using Transformer-Based Camera Link Model and Spatial-Temporal Information Hsiang-Wei Huang, Cheng-Yen Yang, Jenq-Neng Hwang Preprint
- Ki-67 Index Measurement in Breast Cancer Using Digital Image Analysis
   Hsiang-Wei Huang, Wen-Tsung Huang, Hsun-Heng Tsai 2020 Conference on Biomechatronics and Agricultural Machinery
   Engineering

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Computer Vision Research Intern**

Feb 2023 - Apr 2023

Chimei Motor Electronics

Tainan, Taiwan

- Developed a real-time multi-class FCWS (Forward Collision Warning System) for trucks and construction vehicles.
- Improve vehicle LDWS (Lane Departure Warning System) accuracy by 30% under poor visibility condition with auto encoder.
- Provide object tracking and re-identification background knowledge presentation for company's engineering team.

# **Capstone Project Member** *Wyze*

Jan 2022 – Jun 2022

Seattle, WA

- Developed an end to end system that can detect and classify dog breeds using the Vision Transformer model.
- Built a fine-grained object tracker that can track and classify 91 kinds of different objects and 120 breeds of dogs.